Guide to the Stanford University, International Relations Program, Honors Theses SC4-6526 SC4-6526
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Theses, 2001; Accession ARCH_2007_162
  - Luippold, Bard H., The Perfect Storm: Normal Accidents and the Russian Financial Crisis of 1998., May 2001 (Box 2)
  - Lum, Wei Kuan, Catalyzing NATO's Operation Allied Force in Kosovo 1999: The Western Media, the Racak Incident, and the Kosovo Humanitarian Crisis., May 2001 (Box 2)
  - Martos, Sofia, The Role of Race Ideology in Argentine Immigration Discourse., May 2001 (Box 3)
  - Oguntebi, Olufolake A., Uncovering an African Miracle: An Analysis of Constraints to Small and Medium Enterprise Development in Ghana., May 2001 (Box 3)
  - Pollak, Lindsay M., Choosing Europe: Italy and the Dynamics of Public Support for Integration., May 2001 (Box 3)
  - Rosales, Isela M., Immigrant Education Policy: Understanding the Complexities and Challenges of the Immigrant Children Education Dilemma in the United States and Worldwide., May 2001 (Box 3)
  - Schatzberg, Lindsey Diamand, Lives Lost, Lessons Not Learned: A Look at Holding the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees Accountable in the Post-Cold War Period., May 2001 (Box 3)
  - Sharkey, Gary Thomas, Contrasting Concepts of Nationality in Western Europe: Influences on Current Immigration Debate., December 2001 (Box 3)
  - Silver, Mark, Political Prowess and the Preservation of Power: Comparing the Records of Mikhail Gorbachev and Boris Yeltsin., May 2001 (Box 3)
  - Soova, Marje, Reconciling State Interests and Market Incentives In the Market for Higher Education in Estonia., May 2001 (Box 3)
  - Tasar, Eren Mugat, Muslim Life in Kazakstan and Uzbekistan., May 2001 (Box 3)
- Theses, 2003; Accession ARCH_2011_323
  - Eifert, Benn P., The political economy of economic management in postcolonial Zambia, 1964-2002., [circa 2003?]
- Theses, 2004; Accession ARCH_2004_147
  - Ahn, Natalie, International Crisis and Collective Action: Common Security Policy for the European Union after September 11., 5-28-2004 (Box 1)
  - Barath, Barbara, Will the Big Fish Eat the Little Fish?: Policy Options to Address Hungarian Small Farmers After Accession into the European Union., 5-12-2004 (Box 1)
  - Biehl, Amy, Chester Crocker and the Negotiations for Namibian Independence: The Role of the Individual in Recent American Foreign Policy., May 1989 (Box 1)
  - Bilimoria, Nina Y., Words of Mass Destruction: The Media and Democracy in Chile., 5-12-2004 (Box 1)
  - Doktori, Daniel, Under Construction: The United States, the European Union and the Transatlantic Security Paradox., 5-12-2004 (Box 1)
  - Dooling, Patrick J., A Culture of Secrecy: Understanding Information Control Through the Chinese Government's Response to the SARS Epidemic., 5-2004 (Box 1)
  - Galdos, Michelle B., Nazi Bias or Political Genius: An Analysis of the Opportunistic Politics of Juan Domingo Peron., 2004 (Box 1)
  - Grach, Natasha V., "Chto Delat' i Kto Vinovat?": A Cross-Regional Analysis of Corruption in Postcommunist Russia., 5-12-2004 (Box 1)
  - Herlands, Joshua I., Crop Choice in Context: A Case Study of Rice Farmer Decision-Making in Northern Thailand., 5-1-2004 (Box 1)
  - Kirsch, Michael J., Rethinking Varieties of Capitalism: Globalization and Economic Reform in Germany Under Kohl and Schroder., 5-2004 (Box 1)
  - Krampetz, Erin M., We Don't Need No Education?: Decoupling of Girls' Education in Peru., 5-12-2004 (Box 1)
  - Lee, Sabrina H. H., The Law and Economics of International Humanitarian Law., 5-12-2004 (Box 1)
  - Muller, Kenneth J., California in the Global Olive Oil Industry., 6-1-2004 (Box 2)
  - Patel, Dinyar, Building Imperial Delhi: The Politics and Symbolism of a New Capital for India., 5-12-2004 (Box 2)
  - Renick, C. Kiel, Garfuna Perceptions of Globalization: Knowledge, Cultural Erosion, and Cultural Human Rights in Punta Gorda, Belize., 5-12-2004 (Box 2)
  - Rosas, Alexander S., Diversification of the Republic: Muslims and Multiculturalism in Contemporary France., 2004 (Box 2)
  - Sheikholeslam, Sheba, The Harbingers of Revolution: Intellectuals, Modernization, and the Student Movement in Iran., 6-2004 (Box 2)
  - Snavely, Andrea E., Tibetan Identity in Diaspora: A Case Study of the Bay Area., 2004 (Box 2)
  - Swinerton, Kathryn J., The Limits of the Multilateral Trading System: Developing Countries and the GATT/WTO., 5-2004 (Box 2)
  - Wang, Michael L., Khmer Rouge Political Ideology in Thought and Practice., 6-1-2004 (Box 2)
  - Wong, Betty, Development Through R, 5-2004 (Box 2)
- Theses, 2005; Accession ARCH_2005_228
  - Ayala, Elizabeth, "They Should Just Know:" Remittances and implicit family contracts between Salvadoran households and migrants., May 2005 (Box 1)
  - Calzonetti, Claire, Global Visions: An Empirical Analysis of International Coverage in American vs. Foreign News Sources., May 2005 (Box 1)
  - Duncan, Jessie, Playing With Fire: Contemporary Morocccan POlitics Through the Evolution of the Personal Status Law., Spring 2005 (Box 1)
  - Fairbanks, Joseph, An Emerging Divide: How the Diverging Democratic Norms and Foreign Policy Strategies of Russia and the European Union are Preventing Russian Integration into Europe., May 2005 (Box 1)
  - Frerking, Juliet Rose, Religion and state: Muslims under post-communist governments; cases studies in Chechnya, Tatarstan, and Uzbekistan., Sept. 2005 (Box 1)
  - Hill, Katie, Money Talks: The Commercialization of Microfinance in Uganda., Spring 2005 (Box 1)
  - Kim, Jennifer Jihyun, Maximum intervention: an analysis of the United States' occupation of Japan and South Korea in historical, philosophical, and procedural context., 2004-2005 (Box 1)
  - Koo, Gloria Minkyung, Divergence of Perception and Policies: Conceptual and Empirical Analysis of the US-ROK Alliance., May 2005 (Box 1)
  - Lee, Sung, Walking the Tightrope: NGOs and North Korean Refugees in China., Spring 2005 (Box 1)
  - Lustbader, Sarah P., Obligations, Interests, and Reputations: The Impact of International Law On The Use Of Force By The United States Since The Cold War., May 2005 (Box 1)
  - Maylie, Devon, Berlusconi's Image: Television Ownership and Italian Democracy - A Case Study On The Role Media Play In Democratization., May 2005 (Box 2)
  - Munroe, Asha, Reputation and Compliance with International Human Rights Law., 2004-2005 (Box 2)
  - Patel, Amit, The Migration of Latin Americansto Spain: A New Stage for Iberoamerican Partnership., May 2005 (Box 2)
  - Raven, Kate, Carving a Canyon of Tears: The Impacts of Militarization on Community Cohesion in Chiapas, Mexico., June 2005 (Box 2)
  - So, Wan-Chi, Incubating High-Tech Start-Up Companies In Hong Kong: A Survey Of Value-Added Services And Entrepreneurs' Perception Of The Incubation Program In HOng Kong Science And Technology Park (HKSTP)., 2004-2005 (Box 2)
  - Tea, Sok Tieng, Selective Interventions in Africa: A Comparative Study of American Democracy Promotion Efforts., May 2005 (Box 2)
  - Van Fleet, Daniel, An Institutional Analysis of Regional Integration in Latin America: The Case of Mercosur., May 2005 (Box 2)
  - Woltmon, LaCona, Gross National Happiness: Exploring the Bhutanese Alternative to the WEstern Neo-Liberal Economic Development Model., 2004-2005 (Box 2)
- Theses, 2006; Accession ARCH_2006_164
  - Brizius, Erin, Mythic promise: transitional justice and the protection of human rights in Sierra Leone., Spring 2006 (Box 1)
  - Brosman, Gregory Barkley, Protesting Jordan: the role of political mobilization in the liberalization era., May 2006 (Box 1)
  - Burkett, Chelsea, Tiger, Tiger: the ideology of childhood and the use of child soldiers in Sri Lanka., May 2006 (Box 1)
  - Chen, Tan Yan, Internet censorship and discourse: the emergence of public opinion in China., June 2006 (Box 1)
  - Hook, Marcia, Nations within states: the Samaritans and national identity in the modern Middle East., 2006 (Box 1)
  - Kemnitzer, Kristin Anna, Bandages, blankets and Bibles: the role worldview plays in shaping the work of non-governmental organizations in the tsunami relief effort., May 2006 (Box 1)
  - Kim, Gloria Jin, Hearts for a broken homeland: Korean American activism and the politics of North Korean human rights., June 2006 (Box 1)
  - Lam, Kaily Napualani, Venture philanthropy: the sustainability of a hybrid form., June 2006 (Box 1)
  - Lee, Jeffrey K., Women and executive power in Latin America: political and social mechanisms and trends., May 2006 (Box 1)
  - Mela, Maham Abbas, Governance, culture, and economics: how they matter for educational attainment., April 2006 (Box 1)
  - Muzurovic, Admir, Media, politics, and war: the case of Yugoslavia from 1980 to 1991., 2006 (Box 1)
  - Nilson, Peter, The payoff of protectionism: the effect of industry-specific import restrictions on U.S. presidential election outcomes., May 2006 (Box 2)
  - Rissman, Jeffrey, Man of the people: Vladimir Putin and presidential popularity in post-Soviet Russia., May 2006 (Box 2)
  - Scott, Christopher Allen, Koje-do: American POW detention policies during the Korean War., June 2006 (Box 2)
  - Tellez Loucel, Jesus Javier, Environmental politics in the Baja California peninsula: non-government organizations, coalitions, and campaigns., June 2006 (Box 2)
  - Tio, Cathy, University legal aid in Beijing: grassroots realizations and perceptions of Chinese legal reform., May 2006 (Box 2)
- Theses, 2010; Accession ARCH_2010_051
  - An, Vithia Chhean Ny, The effects of democratization on foreign direct investment: a time series analysis of forms of regine and FDI, 1970-1999., 2010 (Box 1)
  - Anchondo, Magdalena, Guatemala's smokescreen: hidden powers, narco-corruption and the culpability of Maras in post war violence., 2010 June (Box 1)
  - Born, Natascha, Evolving German military foreign policy 1990-2010: appeasing international pressure in the face of domestic divisions., 2010 May (Box 1)
  - Cryst, Elena, The curse of the new left: ethnopopulism and inequality in Bolivian social reform., 2010 (Box 1)
  - Flink, Mason, One of them; the United States and the murder of six Jesuit priests in El Salvador., 2010 (Box 1)
  - Forstein, Carolyn, A slow road to justice: the search for rule of law in Post-Soviet Russia., 2010 May (Box 1)
  - Fuetsch, Elena, The effects of regional economic integration on rural development: Paraguay as a case study., 2010 June (Box 1)
  - Glaser, Cady, Destined to diverge: the influence of path dependency on post-communist political and economic trajectories., 2010 May (Box 1)
  - Gregory, Julia, Mom and Pop in modern China: the political economy of urban microbusinesses., 2010 May (Box 1)
  - Kapur, Ariel, Complicit in atrocity: U.S. involvement in the 1996 invasion of the Democratic Republic of the Congo., 2010 June (Box 1)
  - Kapur, Salone, Tweeting for change: how information communication technology (ICT) driven protest movements are creating opportunities for liberalization in authoritarian regimes., 2010 June (Box 1)
  - Lawrence, Andrew, A distraction in the extractive sector: the shortcomings of the extractive industries transparency initiative (EITI) in Azerbaijan., 2010 (Box 1)
  - Martin, Alyssa, Strange bedfellows: secularists, feminists, and Hindu nationalists on the Uniform Civil Code debate in India., 2010 May (Box 1)
  - Meredith, Alexis, Competiton and control: corporate social responsibility in Sierra Leone's mining industry., 2010 (Box 2)
  - Monroe, Steve, Salafis in Parliament: party politics and democratic attitudes in the Gulf., 2010 (Box 2)
  - Ortega, Alejandro G., Disparate democracies: a comparative analysis of Chile and Peru, 1973-2001., 2010 (Box 2)
  - Romero, Lara Sofia, Mapping the Paris-Metropole: cultural planning and citizen politics in an age of democratic distrust., 2010 June (Box 2)
  - Sangokoya, David Adeoluwa, Developing out of displacement: exploring variation in economic recovery of Northern Uganda and other countries following displacement-inducing conflict., 2010 May (Box 2)
  - Shakro, Peter, Answering the call: the joint effects of punitive public opinion and institutional responsiveness on incarceration rates in contemporary Western democracies., 2010 May (Box 2)
- Theses, 1978-1998; Accession ARCH-2017-302
  - Billa, Ben, The limits of liberal freedom: an argument for equality in development, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Feler, Leo, Growth and Empowerment: Stategies to Alleviate Poverty in Brazil, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Sholts, Crystal, From Kiosk to Couture: Conspicuous Consumption in Post-Soviet Moscow, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Auerbach, Tracey, Intellectuals, Ideas, and Economic Policy: The Case of the "Chicago Boys" in Chile, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Austin, Jon, The European Union in Regional Development, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Brutlag, Benjamin, Construction through Compromise: Developing a Common European Foreign Policy, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Coffman, Makena, The Relationship Between Trade and Forests, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Cohen, Leah, Moving Backwards?: A Case of Arrested Development in Russian Agriculture, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Cohen, Seth, From Italians to Europeans: The Potential and Limits of a European Citizenship, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Cowan-Nava, Kim, The Politicization of Healthcare: Immigrant Access to Medicaid in California and Texas, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Garrett, Kenneth, The International Olympic Committeee and the German Question, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Fraser, Liz, The Accession of the Czech Republic by the European Union: A Cost Benefit Analysis, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Inouye, Lauren, The Role of Government in Promoting Industrial Environmental Technology Transfer to the Industrialized World, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Kaske, Clea, A Global Road To Justice?: An Organizational and Institutional comparison between the International Criminal Tribunal for the Former Yugoslavia and the International Criminal Court and the impact of US Involvement in both courts, 2003 (Box 1)
  - Lacanlale, Alarice, The Quest for Equity: The Implications of Land Reform in the Philippines Aquino Administration 1986-1992, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Leonberger, Katie, Regional Welfare in Chile: An Empirical Analysis of Welfare Across Time and the Impacts of Economic Growth, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Ochoa, Don, International Economic Organizations and the Process of Accession: Suggestions from a Mexican Case Study, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Person, Robert, Wither Russia?: An Analysis of Russian Foreign Policy under Vladimir Putin, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Pietsch, Molly, The 1978 Court Interpreters Act: An Analsis of its Purpose, Creation, and Implementation, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Reed, Nicholas, Confidence and Current Crises: An Analysis of the United States' Ability to Maintain and Restore Monetary Stability, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Russell Garnett, Susan, The Transition to Democracy and the Legacy of Human Rights Violations in Argentina, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Small, Andres, A Bid for Mexican Democracy: An Empirical Case Study of the Campaign Spending Strategy Employed by Political Acttors in Mexico's 2000 Elections, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Soledad, Gabe, The Erosion of Power: Resources and Democracy in Mexico, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Stan, Anreea, Anchoring Inflation in Transition Economies: the Case for a Currency Board Arrangement in Romania, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Sulmeyer, Michael, Power in the Kremlin: The Rationale Behind Russia's Invasion of Chechnya in December 1994, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Tan, Yeling, Women's Empoerment Through Microfinance: Evidence from Nepal and Bangladesh, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Torrence, Jesse, Beyond Ecotourism: Searching Chile for a better tourism-based development model, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Vermazen, Kathleen, The Story Matters: Framing and the First Russo-Chechen War, 1994-1996, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Ahmed, Sameer, Opening the Kingdom: Can Saudi Arabia Liberalize?, 2003 (Box 2)
  - Ahn, Jenny, Engaging North Korea: Lessons from the Agreed Framework, 2003 (Box 2)
  - Bailey, Laura, Foreign Direct Invenstment in Russia after 1991: Prblems and Prospects, 2003 (Box 2)
  - Chen, Julie, The French Juvenile Justice System: The Ordinance of 1945 in the 1900s, 2003 (Box 2)
  - Cornell, Phillip, U.S.-European Security Relations after the Cold War: An Institutional-Culturalist Approach to Divergence, 2003 (Box 2)
  - Daniel, Mary, From Rivals to Partners in Nuclear Weapons Nonproliferation: A Study of the Influence of the Atoms for Peace Program on Nuclear Posture in Argentina and Brazil, 2003 (Box 2)
  - Diesen, Claire, Looking to the "Dutch Miracle" to Cure German Unemployment, 2003 (Box 2)
  - Dubal, Veena, The Intersection of Race and National Belonging: A History of South Asians in Northern California, 2003 (Box 2)
  - Eifert, Benn, The Political Economy of Economic Management in Postcolonial Zambia: 1964-2002, 2003 (Box 2)
  - Elias, Rebecca, Creating Corporate Responsibility in Ecuador's Oil Industry: The Influence of Advocacy Networks, 2003 (Box 2)
  - Greninger, Alex, The Changing Face of European Football: Toward a European Super League?, 2003 (Box 2)
  - Grose, Jared, Fear, Behavior, and Health Care in Rural Guatemala, 2003 (Box 2)
  - Jayaram, Keya, Playing with Fire: An Analysis of the Root Causes of Child Soldier Use in Post-1990 Civil Wars, 2003 (Box 2)
  - Lee, Jeffrey, The Failure of Political Islam in Indonesia: Why the World's largest Muslim-populated nation has never had Islamic Government, 2003 (Box 2)
  - Liu, Josephine, The Asian Monetary Fund: A Study in Monetary Conflict and Cooperation, 2003 (Box 2)
  - Long, Tianying Amy, From Political to Personal: China's Party Press in a Globalized Media Industry, 2003 (Box 2)
  - Lundgren, Kari, The Relative Effectiveness of International Environmental Conventions: A Case Study of Two Conventions and Their Regulation of Nutrient Pollution in the Baltic and North East Atlantic, 2003 (Box 2)
  - Magee, Joshua, The Effects of the Kyoto Protocol's "Flexibility Mechanisms" on the Polish Coal Industry, 2003 (Box 2)
  - Nadal, Sara, An Investigation of the Effects of Dollarization on the Economic Welfare of Ecuador's Poor, 2003 (Box 2)
  - Naunheim, Kate, Charting Change in Human Rights Practices in China Effected by NGO Advocacy: Roadblocks to Efficacy and Prospects for Change, 2003 (Box 2)
  - Neril, Jonathan, Genetically Modified Corn in Oaxaca, Mexico: Implications for Indigenous Communities, Biodiversity, and International Trade, 2003 (Box 2)
  - Samarasinghe, Leshika, Why Peoplization? Understanding the Sri Lankan Decision to Privatize, 2003 (Box 2)
  - Steinberg, Matthew, A Flawed Approach to State Building: The Office of the High Representative in Bosnia and Herzegovina, 2003 (Box 2)
  - Stone, Meryl, The Inevitable Solution? The Conflictual Dynamics of Israeli Identity, the Peace Process and Palestinian Statehood, 2003 (Box 2)
  - Yoo, Karen, Integration Issues: A Comparison of the Situation of Koreans in Japan and Ethnic Algerians in France, 2003 (Box 2)
  - Ahn, Natalie, Internaional Crisis and Collective Action: Common Security Policy for the European Union after September, 2004 (Box 3)
  - Barath, Barbara, Will the Big Fish Eat the Little Fish?: Policy options to address Hungarian small farmers after accession into the European Union, 2004 (Box 3)
  - Bilimoria, Nina, Words of Mass Destruction: The Media and Democracy in Chile, 2004 (Box 3)
  - Chi So, Wan, Incubating High-tech Start-Up Companies in Hong Kong: A Survey of Value-Added Services and Entrepreneurs' Perception of the Incubation Program in Hong Kong Science and Technology Park (HKSTP), 2004 (Box 3)
  - Doktori, Dan, Under Construction: The United States, the European Union and the Transatlantic Security Paradox, 2004 (Box 3)
  - Dooling, Patrick, A Culture of Secrecy: Understanding Information Control through the Chinese Government's Response to the SARS Epidemic, 2004 (Box 3)
  - Galdos, Michelle, Nazi Bias or Political Genius: An Analysis of the Opportunistic Politics of Juan Domingo Peron, 2004 (Box 3)
  - Grach, Natasha, "Chto Delat' I Kto Vinovat?": A Cross-Regional Analysis of Corruption in Postcommunist Russia, 2004 (Box 3)
  - Herlands, Josh, Crop Choice in Context: A Case Study of Rice Farmer Decision-Making in North Thailand, 2004 (Box 3)
  - Kirsch, Michael Jacob, Rethinking Varieties of Capitalism: Globalism Economic Reform in Germany Under Kohl Schroder, 2004 (Box 3)
  - Krampetz, Erin McClure, We Don't Need No Education?: Decoupling of Girls' Education in Peru, 2004 (Box 3)
  - Lee, Sabrina, The Law and Economics of International Humanitarian Law, 2004 (Box 3)
  - Liu, Lily, The New Cooperative Medical System in Yunnan Province, 2004 (Box 3)
  - Muller, Ken, California in the Global Olive Oil Industry, 2004 (Box 3)
  - Patel, Dinyar, Building Imperial Delhi: The Politics and Symbolism of a New Capital for India, 2004 (Box 3)
  - Renick, Kiel, Garifuna Perceptions of Globalization: Knowledge, Culteral Erosion, and Culteral Human Rights in Punta Gorda, Belize, 2004 (Box 3)
  - Root, Megan, Corporate Responsibility in Chinese Companies: The Legacy of Socialism, 2004 (Box 3)
  - Rosas, Alex, Diversity of the Republic: Muslims and Multiculteralism in Contemporary France, 2004 (Box 3)
  - Sheikholeslam, Sheba, The Harbingers of Revolution: Intellectuals, Modernization, and the Student Movement in Iran, 2004 (Box 3)
  - Swinerton, Kathryn, The Limits of the Multilateral Trading System: Developing Countries and the GATT/WTO, 2004 (Box 3)
  - Snavely, Andrea, Tibetan Identity in Diaspora: A Case Study of the Bay Area, 2004 (Box 3)
  - Wang, Michel, Khmer Rouge Political Ideology In Thought And Practice, 2004 (Box 3)
  - Woltmon, LaCona, Gross National Happiness: Exploring the Bhutanese Alternative to the Western Neo-Liberal Economic Development Model, 2004 (Box 3)
  - Wong, Betty, Development Through R, 2004 (Box 3)
  - Ayala, Elizabeth, "They Should Just Know": Remittances and Implicit Family Contracts between Salvadoran Households and Migrants, 2005 (Box 3)
  - Calzonetti, Claire, Global Visions: An Empirical Analysis of International Coverage in American vs. Foreign News Sources, 2005 (Box 3)
  - Duncan, Jessie, Playing with Fire: Contemporary Moroccan Politics Through the Evolution of the Personal Status Law, 2005 (Box 3)
  - Fairbanks, Joseph, An Emerging Divide: How the Diverging Democratic Norms and Foreign Policy Strategies of Russia and the European Union are Preventing Russian Integration into Europe, 2005 (Box 3)
  - Frerking, Juliet, Religion and the State: Muslims under Post-Communist Governments Case Studies in Chechnya, Tatarstan, and Uzbekistan, 2005 (Box 3)
  - Hill, Katie, Money Talks: The Commercialization of Microfinance in Uganda, 2005 (Box 3)
  - Kim, Jennifer, MaximumIntervention: An Analysis of the United States' Occupationo f Japan and South Korea in Historical, Philosophical, and Procedural Context, 2005 (Box 4)
  - Lee, Sung, Walking the Tightrope: NGOs and North Korean Refugees in China, 2005 (Box 4)
  - Lustbader, Sarah, Obligations, Interests, and Reputations: The Impact of International Law on the Use of Force by the United States Since the Cold War, 2005 (Box 4)
  - Maylie, Devon, Berlusconi's Image: Television Ownership and Italian Democracy A Case Study on the Role Media Play in Democratization, 2005 (Box 4)
  - Minkyung Koo, Gloria, Divergence of Perceptions and Policies: Conceptual and Empirical Analysis of the US-ROK Alliance, 2005 (Box 4)
  - Munroe, Asha, Reputation and Compliance with International Human Rights Law, 2005 (Box 4)
  - Patel. Amit, The Migration of Latin Americans to Spain: A New Stage for Iberoamerican Partnership, 2005 (Box 4)
  - Raven, Kate, Carving a Canyon of Tears: The Impacts of Militarization on Community Cohesion in Chiapas, Mexico, 2005 (Box 4)
  - Tea, Sok, Selective Interventions in Africa: A Comparative Study of American Democracy Promotion Efforts, 2005 (Box 4)
  - Van Fleet, Daniel, An Institutional Analysis of Regional Interaction in Latin America: The Case of Mercosur, 2005 (Box 4)